tailwind a massive collection of tiny css utility classes for quickly and
tailwind 大量的微型css 实用程序类集合，用于快速、
consistently building good-looking websites css is hard design is also hard
一致地构建漂亮的网站 css 很难设计也很难，
but naming your css classes in a sane way is virtually impossible frameworks
但是以理智的方式命名你的 css 类几乎是不可能的，
like bootstrap and material address this challenge by creating styles for high
像 bootstrap 和 material 这样的框架通过创建高的样式来解决这个挑战
level components things like buttons drop downs and forms tailwind takes a
级别组件之类的按钮下拉菜单和表单tailwind
more functional approach by providing you with utility classes that can be
通过为您提供实用程序类来提供更实用的方法，这些实用程序类可以
composed together to build components like this instead of using the card
组合在一起以构建这样的组件，而不是像您在引导程序中那样使用卡片
class like you might in bootstrap you combine utility classes like flex to
类您可以组合像 flex 这样的实用程序类来
make it a flexbox p to give it padding m for margin and hundreds of others to
制作 它是一个 flexbox p 来给它填充 m作为边距，还有数百个其他的
control things like color shadows and so on in addition every utility can be
东西来控制颜色阴影等东西。此外，每个实用程序都可以
applied conditionally you have variants like small medium and large for
有条件地应用，你有像小型和大型这样的变体，用于
responsive designs along with a bunch of pseudo-selectors like hover and focus to
响应式设计以及一堆伪 选择器像悬停和焦点来
handle state changes or dark to render different colors when dark mode is
处理状态变化或黑暗来呈现不同的颜色时
enabled this approach gives you a lot more freedom over your creativity
启用暗模式 与其他 css 框架相比，这种方法为您的创造力提供了更多的自由，
compared to other css frameworks while at the same time following the rules of
同时遵循
a design system that you don't get with plain css it lives in the sweet spot
设计系统的规则，这是普通 css 无法获得的，它位于约定和之间的最佳位置
between convention and configuration however it does produce some ugly ass
配置但是它确实会产生一些丑陋的
html you've got tons of hard to read duplicated class names here as your ui
html 你有很多难以阅读的重复类名，因为你的 ui
grows in complexity code duplication is inevitable but you can avoid it by
变得越来越复杂，代码重复是不可避免的，但你可以通过
creating reusable components with your favorite javascript framework or by
使用你最喜欢的 javascript 框架创建可重用组件或
using the apply directive in css to take tailwind classes and compose them into a
使用 在 css 中应用指令来获取tailwind 类并将它们组合成
single concise class name another concern you may have is performance
一个简洁的类名您可能需要担心的另一个问题是性能，
because tailwind weighs in at over 3 500 kilobytes but when you go to build for
因为 tailwind 的重量超过 3 500KB，但是当您进行
production it will automatically purge any unused utility from the final bundle
生产时，它会自动清除任何未使用的实用程序 最终捆绑
resulting in minimal dead code and thus faster page loads but who has time to
导致最少的死代码，从而更快的页面加载，但谁有时间
learn and memorize all these different utility classes where tailwind really
学习和记住所有这些不同的uti  tailwind 真正
shines is with its tooling you don't need to memorize much because vs code
闪耀的 lity 类是它的工具，你不需要记住太多，因为如果你不确定它做什么，vs code
will auto-complete every tailwind class if you're not sure what it does just
会自动完成每个 tailwind 类，只需将
hover over it and it will show you the equivalent code in plain css and if
鼠标悬停在它上面，它就会向你显示等效的代码 普通的 css，如果
you're not happy with what it does you can easily customize everything from the
您对它的功能不满意，您可以轻松自定义从
color palette to the spacing to build your own unique design system this has
调色板到间距的所有内容，以构建您自己独特的设计系统，这
been tailwind css in 100 seconds make sure to like and subscribe if you want
在 100 秒内成为顺风 css，如果您愿意，请确保喜欢并
to see more short videos like this and if we hit 10 000 likes i'll make a full
订阅 看更多这样的短视频，如果我们达到 10 000 个赞，我会制作一个完整的
tailwind tutorial thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
顺风教程 感谢观看，我会在下一个